{
    "uid": "c5620534-6450-4f97-9ccb-1644fc3ebc8e",
    "title": "MITRE ATT&CK Challenge 1",
    "instructions": "<p>Prompting an active incident response scenario at <b>Permalink Software</b>, the SOC team noticed an unusual spike in traffic from one of their endpoints,  communicating with a known malicious IP address. This activity was flagged by the network intrusion detection system (NIDS) and correlated with other indicators of compromise found in threat intelligence feeds.</p><p>Your task is to use your knowledge of the <a href=\"https://attack.mitre.org/\" target=\"_blank\">MITRE ATT&CK</a> framework and TTPs to help guide the team through identifying and reconstructing the attack kill chain. By doing so, the SOC can better understand the nature of the compromise and formulate a response plan.</p>",
  
  
    "questions": [
        {
            "quid": "8c47c31d",
            "question": "The investigation revealed that a large spike in network traffic originated from an external IP address. The majority of this traffic was generated by a suspicious user-agent string: <code>Mozilla/5.0 (compatible; Nmap Scripting Engine;)</code> and appears to be aimed at identifying <b>vulnerabilities</b>. What is the ID of this specific <b>sub-technique</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1595.002"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "30d22dc5",
            "question": "What is the <b>name</b> of the main <b>technique</b> this falls under?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["Active Scanning"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "4daff48e",
            "question": "The SOC later discovered that the adversary exploited one of the organization's external software applications through an <b>SQL injection</b> vulnerability. What is the MITRE <b>technique</b> ID that led to the attacker's initial access?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1190"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "0837b8ab",
            "question": "It was later discovered that the <code>sqlmap</code> tool was used to automate the process of detecting and exploiting the SQL injection vulnerability. What is the MITRE ID pertaining to this piece of <b>software</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["S0225"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "c0adc33b",
            "question": "After achieving remote code execution through the SQL injection vulnerability, the attacker created a remote reverse shell on the server by initiating a <code>cmd.exe</code> process. What <b>sub-technique</b> ID does this relate to?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1059.003"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "9f096d9d",
            "question": "The attacker <b>escalated privileges</b> by impersonating an administrator user's security token and abusing the <code>SeImpersonatePrivilege</code>. According to MITRE, what is one of the <b>API calls</b> that can be monitored to <b>detect</b> this behavior?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The keyword for this technique is <b>Token Impersonation</b>.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["DuplicateToken", "DuplicateToken(Ex)", "ImpersonateLoggedOnUser", "SetThreadToken"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "ce6bdcd4",
            "question": "During the initial live incident response triage, a responder noticed that an existing Windows <b>service</b> had its image path modified to point to the attackerâ€™s malicious reverse shell payload - likely to establish persistence. What is the ID of this <b>sub-technique</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1543.003"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "bdab56ec",
            "question": "Around the same timeframe, endpoint logs in the SIEM reported that the system's <b>Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR)</b> tool was turned off and <b>disabled</b>. What <b>sub-technique</b> ID is this event likely referring to?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1562.001"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "7fd3577f",
            "question": "The <code>ccf32</code> <b>software</b> was transferred to the host shortly after the initial compromise. What <b>tactic</b> is this software likely used for?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["Collection", "TA0009"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "bba8a040",
            "question": "After staging sensitive data, files, and intellectual property, the attacker <b>exfiltrated</b> the data by pushing it to a public <b>GitHub repository</b>. What <b>mitigation</b> ID could the organization have implemented to prevent the use of unauthorized external services?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "GitHub is a <b>code repository</b>.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["M1021", "Restrict Web-Based Content"]
        },
        {
            "quid": "ffcc7362",
            "question": "To complete the adversary's Actions on Objectives, the organization's <b>public-facing</b> corporate website was <b>modified</b> to display propaganda messages during the attack. What is the full <b>sub-technique</b> ID of this attack?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["T1491.002"]
        }
    ]
  }